What?
That leg is all beat up.
I know, but what else am I
supposed to do? It's all I've got.
Better bring my crutch, just to be safe.
But I told you I'd be your leg for you!
No, thank you.
I never asked for that in the first place.
What's got you all pouty?
It's nothing.
But seeing you rely on that old beat-up thing
so much does make me a little jealous.
What?
Losing out to that glorified peg leg
besmirches my good name as a robot.
I have to prove that these high
specs
of mine aren't just for show!
Natsuki, I—
Yeah, no thanks.
I haven't even said anything yet!
Don't you dare get any funny ideas, got it?
You coming, or what?
Huh? Where are we...
School's gonna start without you.
You're coming, too?
Wait for me! I have to be your leg!
You're gonna want one of these.
Gotta take notes in class.
Thank you! Now I can start keeping logs!
Logs?
That's right!
Nonko told me to do it so I can have a record
of what happened on any given day.
Sounds low-tech.
Can't you just store
that information in your memory?
I can.
But apparently this would help me develop
more human-like memory storage faculties.
Maybe having you lose your memories was
an intentional effort to make you seem more human.
You're so smart, Natsuki!
That's exactly it!
Clearly, my memory loss is proof
positive
of my astronomically high—
Yeah, let's not go that far.
"Going to school with Natsuki."
That's all?
No peeking! That's a violation
of the Robot Autonomous Privacy Act!
Welp.
We just have to cross!
With my incredible long jump skills,
a gap like this isn't even a—
Yeah, not happening.
But...
If we swim, we'll get our clothes wet.
Not what I mean.
Kids get in and out every day, right?
There's gotta be some easier way to—
Hold it right there!
Wh-What in the world?!
You're not going anywhere, hitman!
Hitman?
We know all about you!
You're an evil hired gun
from the mainland, aren't you?
We've heard the stories.
You have a rifle hidden in your crutch,
and you're not afraid to use it!
Oh. That's the game we're playing, huh?
If you wanna take on Natsuki,
you'll have to get through me first!
Back off, pipsqueak!
Pipsqueak?!
You heard her, pipsqueak.
Not you too, Natsuki!
Sorry, but I've got very important
business at your school.
If you don't want to eat lead from my machine crutch,
you'd best get outta my way.
R-Ririka, what do we do?
T-Tactical retreat! Run for it!
After 'em, Atri.
Huh?
Hurry up.
Mwahaha! You'll never take us alive!
Weren't we supposed to be the bad guys?
We have to follow them!
With my flawless long
jump technique,
a gap like this is—
No need.
Huh?
Ririka, look!
Aah, I forgot!
Okay, let's go.
This floor's totally empty.
He's coming!
So that's where they were.
All right, boys and girls! Time for class!
Minamo?
Take your seats, everyone.
Minamo!
We've got trouble! The hitman's here!
Run for your life!
Hitman?
Freeze!
Natsu!
Natsu?
Isn't he the hitman? And—
The pipsqueak!
I'm no pipsqueak!
Yeah.
She's got a name, and it's
Bootleg Humanoid McToaster the Third.
You mean Atri!
You really came!
I'm not gonna stick around
after class starts, though.
Where's the teacher?
Um...
You're real clueless, huh?
Minamo's our teacher!
She teaches us language arts,
math, science, social studies, everything!
You're the teacher?
Yeah.
All our teachers already evacuated to the mainland.
'Cause, you know,
there's barely any students left...
My dad wants me to shut everything down
and do the paperwork to transfer to the mainland.
I mean, you can hardly call
this place a functioning school.
Yeah...
We don't even have electricity,
so we can only have class when it's light out.
I know these kids deserve better, but...
You'll be fine either way,
but you should at least send them to
the
mainland so they can get a decent education.
They have aid programs for disaster victims, too.
Shut up, dude. Don't act like
you understand a single thing about us.
Ryuu!
What would you even know?
You're just some fancy-pants elite
who abandoned us to go to the Academy.
I didn't abandon anything.
I studied hard and enrolled in the Academy
so I could make a difference.
That's all.
Then get started on that already.
Ever since you came back,
you've just been moping around on your boat.
At least we're making an honest effort here.
Ryuu!
You sound just like the mainlanders.
You talk a big game about making a difference,
but all you do is sit on your ass
while the rest of us suffer.
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
Bye-bye, Atri! See you tomorrow!
Bye! See you all tomorrow!
Looks like you've made some new friends, huh?
Yes. School is much more fun than I was expecting.
What were you expecting?
I had this feeling that school was a very sad place.
Oh, that's just silly. Right, Natsu?
Sorry. I should've just stayed home.
No, you didn't do anything wrong.
I'm sure Ryuu knows that, too.
He's just had some bad experiences
on the mainland, that's all.
He has?
Yeah.
Those kids lost their parents,
so he tried bringing them over to the mainland.
But, you know, folks over there
are also struggling to get by,
so the kids ended up getting ostracized at school.
Natsuki looks sad.
Yeah. Cheer him up when you get home, okay?
Me?
Of course!
You know, Natsu,
I'd really appreciate it if you came back tomorrow.
What's the point?
Not like there's anything for you to teach me.
Yeah, but there's plenty for you to teach us.
I'll think about it.
Hey, where'd Atri go?
She said she was going on ahead.
You gave her your permission.
Huh? Oh, guess I did.
She wanted to prepare a nice surprise for you.
A nice surprise?
Oh no!
It's okay! You don't have to panic!
I'm sure she just wants to make
a nice dinner for you and—
Uh-oh.
Atri!
Welcome home, Natsuki!
H-Huh? I can't see...
I can't see a thing!
Explain yourself.
I, uh, thought it might cheer you up
if I made you a tasty dinner...
How does cooking lead to a mess like this?
W-Well, as I've said before,
in a way, making human-like mistakes
is actually proof of my stupendously high specs!
It's not even humanly possible
to screw up this badly.
Maybe some part of her is malfunctioning?
Huh?
Could be. And I don't have any way
to repair her, either.
Guess I'd better chuck her back into the sea.
What?!
Wanna explain how you caused
this catastrophe, then?
U-Uh, that's easy...
You see, the truth is...
What is it?
The truth is, I'm a top-secret lethal autonomous robot
developed by a foreign government.
Really?!
Yes.
I infiltrated this country
to take it down from within...
But the war came to an end
before I could carry out my mission.
I lost not only my homeland,
but my very reason for existence.
There I found myself, a poor,
lonely killing machine with nowhere to go.
But in my moment of greatest despair,
Nonko found me.
She took me in, gave me a name,
and a new purpose.
And that was...
Doing housework...
Exactly.
But as a specialized combat unit,
controlling my strength is—
Atri.
Yes?
Humanoids can lie, can they?
Yes! But of course!
I'm high-spec, baby!
All of that was a lie?!
Don't you think this violates
the Humanoid Anti-Abuse Act?
She'll survive. She doesn't even need food, anyway.
If you ask me, a robot lying to
its master is a much bigger problem.
Objection, Your Honor!
One, I am a robot.
Two, I am hopeless at housework.
From these two indisputable facts,
simple deductive reasoning
leads to the eminently logical conclusion
that I am almost certainly a deadly—
Then hit me with your best shot.
A war machine like you's
gotta at least have some missiles, yeah?
Y-You asked for it!
Rocket pun—
On second thought, I'd better not.
I must obey the Three Laws of Robotics,
and I can hardly guarantee your survival.
You live to see another day, Natsuki.
Why is running your mouth
the one thing you're good at?
Because my speech apparatus is super high—
Shut up.
You know, Atri,
I think you've really cheered Natsu up.
Really?!
Here, come eat with us.
I think this egg came out nicely!
Don't waste our food!
Très bien!
I swear...
See you two tomorrow!
Please pack extra eggs for lunch!
What makes you think you're getting any?!
I'll graciously taste test your food
and deliver my discerning verdict.
A feat only made possible
by my downright preposterous specs!
Oh, I'd better update my logs...
Huh?
What's up?
It's gone.
Huh?
I think I left my logbook at school!
Can't this wait until tomorrow?
Absolutely not. Logs are of vital importance!
You'd think you wouldn't forget it, then.
It sure is dark...
Nighttime generally is.
That's not what I meant.
D-Did you see that?
Are you scared, Natsuki?
N-No!
That was totally weird, right?
We don't have electricity on this island.
Aw, are you a widdle scaredy-cat?
Poor baby.
It's all right. When we get back you can cuddle
with me again as much as you want!
Ooh, you're just too precious!
Wait! Violence isn't the answer, Natsuki!
The floor's flooded with seawater.
It was totally dry earlier, too...
High tide...
Of course. That's why there wasn't
anything on the second floor.
I-I knew I saw something earlier...
Switching to high-sensitivity mode!
It looks like a person! Atri, away!
Hey! Atri!
Hey, Atri?
Atri...
Found it!
So, what about the light?
There was nobody there.
You said you saw a person.
What if it was a... ghooost?
Knock it off.
They might've gone upstairs.
Didn't know you can access the roof.
Looks like nobody's here.
Maybe it really was a ghooost?
You're a robot. Stick to the scientific.
But...
That's them! My eyes never lie!
Wh-Who's there?
Huh? The hitman?
Huh?
Hey, it is you.
Ririka!
What're you doing here?
What do you mean?
I live here, stupid.
Huh? You live here?
Not just me, either.
Ryuu and Tooru, too.
All our houses sunk into the sea.
Aw, couldn't the wind have held out a little longer?
I was almost done reading this, too...
An electricity textbook...
I've got nothing better to do at night,
so I bring this up from the library.
Thought there might be a way
to bring electricity back to the island.
Hey.
Ryuuji?
What're you doing here, huh?
Here. 'S not much,
but I brought a few snacks.
Thanks!
Any batteries?
Sorry. Looked all over, but I couldn't find any.
Oh.
Thanks anyway!
Listen, don't strain yourself
tryna read that. It's bad for your eyes.
Get some sleep soon.
Okay!
This is life for us.
Those of us who have nothing,
we get chased off the mainland
before we can accomplish anything.
But start off in a better position,
and apparently you get whatever you want.
We want to study so we can change something,
but we don't even get to do that much.
Guess it's worth a shot.
Natsuki! Where were you?
Hey, when you're done writing that,
can you help me spin the turbine outside?
Sure, but why?
I have an idea I wanna test.
Here goes!
Yeah, go for it!
Should I keep going?
Yeah! Gimme more juice!
What?!
Put your back into it!
You're a combat robot, aren't you?
Ngh... this is borderline robot cruelty!
Looks like efficiency really does
suffer on such a small scale.
But a bigger turbine would come
with its own problems...
That's it!
Natsuki, can I stop yet?
Natsukiii...
Natsuki?
Natsuki, you dirty boy...
Natsuki? Huh?!
Oh, you're up.
Get ready soon, or we're gonna be late.
Have you been working all night long?
Sure.
At the Academy, we called it Tuesday.
Anyway, I'm bringing something
for show-and-tell today.
Mind carrying it for me?
You're coming?
Yeah.
All right, class, I've invited a special guest
lecturer
today for a super special lesson!
A guest lecturer?
Who is it?
Let's give him a warm welcome!
Oh. The hitman.
Keep your disappointment to yourself!
I've got feelings too, you know.
What's that?
Some stuff I scrounged up around town last night.
A lightbulb, a motor, a pinwheel, and a dry cell.
Aw, what?
That ain't gonna last long without wind, genius.
Sure won't.
That's why it gets thrown out with the trash,
even on this island,
where we need everything we can get.
But with a little ingenuity, even junk like this...
It's so bright!
Yeah, so long as the wind holds up.
Right.
But what if we could store
the electricity we're generating?
No way! You can store wind energy?
Takes some extra effort, but yeah.
You want a medal or something?
Ryuu...
There's only so much electricity
a tiny little pinwheel like that can make.
Stop getting their hopes up.
You're not wrong. But what if it wasn't so tiny?
What? You think you're gonna
be able to build us a giant turbine?
Like hell that's gonna happen.
Is it really out of the question?
Besides, wind isn't the only way
to generate electricity.
There's thermal power, water power, nuclear power,
geothermal power, and not to mention...
The sea?
You can make electricity with the sea?
Yeah.
Lucky for us, this school is sitting right in it,
and the second floor gets flooded at high tide.
We can take advantage of that.
Natsu!
Get real, man!
What about materials, huh?
Everything halfway useful
on this island is already—
Not everything.
Huh?
There's a whole treasure trove of goodies
out there ripe for the taking!